graphql a query language for reading and mutating data in apis
graphql 一种查询语言，用于作为后端开发人员在 apis 中读取和修改数据
as a back-end developer graphql provides a type system
graphql 提供了一个类型系统
where you can describe a schema for your data in turn
，您可以在其中描述数据的模式，
this gives front-end consumers of the api the power to explore
这使api 的前端消费者能够探索
and request the exact data they need traditionally
和请求确切的数据 他们需要的数据传统上，
web developers have consumed apis using rest where data entities
Web 开发人员使用 api 使用休息方式，其中数据实体
live on a bunch of urls on a server when a request is received
存在于服务器上的一堆 url 上，当收到请求时
the api responds with the full data payload of that entity
，api 会使用该实体的完整数据有效负载进行响应，
that sounds simple enough but there are two potential drawbacks here
这听起来很简单，但这里有两个潜在的缺点
we may need multiple entities at one time in which case
我们可能一次需要多个实体，在这种情况下，
each request is under fetching the actual data we want
每个请求都在获取我们想要的实际数据，而
in other cases we may only want a small subset of a data entity
在其他情况下，我们可能只需要数据实体的一小部分，
in which case we need to over fetch from the api and that of course is bad for
在这种情况下，我们需要从 api 中过度获取，当然 对环境不好
the environment how dare you instead of multiple urls a
你怎么敢而不是多个 url 一个
graphql api has a single entry point data is queried
graphql api有一个入口点
or fetched by describing it with a syntax that
通过使用反映其 retu 的语法来描述它来查询或获取数据
mirrors its return shape in json the front-end developer describes the
rn shape injson 前端开发人员描述
data they want while the back-end developer
他们想要的数据，而后端开发人员
writes code to resolve the request and it all happens in a syntax that can work
编写代码来解决请求，这一切都发生在可以
with any programming language we can start defining a schema with our
与任何编程语言一起使用的语法中，我们可以开始使用我们
own custom objects using the type keyword
自己的自定义定义模式 使用 type关键字
a type can have multiple fields like a unique id
的对象 一个类型可以有多个字段，例如一个唯一的 id
and we'll make that required with a bang let's also give it integer and string
，我们将用一个 bang 使其成为必需让我们也给它整数和字符串
values then create a relationship with another
值，然后创建与另一个
type a creator can have many videos which we can represent by wrapping the
类型的关系 创建者可以拥有许多我们可以代表的视频 通过将
type in brackets on the flip side a video belongs to a creator now every
类型包装在另一侧的括号中，视频属于创建者现在每个
graphql api has a query type which is the main entry
graphql api都有一个查询类型，它是
point for a consumer of the api we can query a list of videos or an
api 消费者的主要入口点，我们可以根据他们查询视频列表或
individual user based on their id that's how a consumer reads data but
单个用户 id这就是消费者读取数据的方式，但
they may also want to mutate data in which case we implement a mutation
他们可能还想改变数据，在这种情况下，我们实现了一个突变
type that defines how data can be modified on the api
类型，它定义了如何在
from there we can define code to resolve this data in any programming language
api 上修改数据，我们可以定义要解析的代码
once deployed any developer consuming this api will be able to explore it with
一旦部署了任何编程语言中的此数据，任何使用此 API 的开发人员都将能够在
a complete understanding of all possible queries and data
完全了解所有可能的查询和数据
entities which means the tooling can autocomplete your query as you type it
实体的情况下探索它，这意味着该工具可以在您在编辑器中输入查询时自动完成您的查询
out in your editor this has been graphql in 100 seconds if
graphql 在 100 秒内如果
you want to see more short videos like this make sure to like and subscribe and
你想看更多这样的短视频，请确保喜欢并订阅并
turn on notifications because there is a lot more on the way
打开通知，因为还有更多的内容
thanks for watching and i will see you in the next one
感谢观看，我会在下一个看到你